We have to follow the advice of the mahājana.
Мы должны следовать совету великой души
[Karma | Motive of Movement]
[Карма. Движущий мотив]
… because both are the same in terms of external movement,
…поскольку внешне оба действия могут выглядеть одинаково,
but one is moving under the faithful plane, under the advice of Guru and Vaiṣṇava.
но одно продиктовано верой, советом гуру и вайшнава...
Sādhu, Śāstra, Guru, and Vaiṣṇava, you’re moving in the faithful plane.
Садху, шастры, гуру и вайшнавы — вы следуете в мире веры.
So, you’re sheltered. What you’re doing is akarmic, it’s divine,
И тогда вы находитесь под защитой. Ваши действия становятся акармой, от Бога.
it will be nourishing, progressive; it’s everything.
Это будет придавать вам сил, помогать идти вперёд; в этом всё.
It’s life giving— eternally life giving.
Оно жизнетворно, вечно жизнетворно.
The same exact movements for another reason are vikarma;
Но те же самые действия, когда у них другая цель, будут викармой;
it will take you down, will ruin you. The same exact movements.
они будут тянуть вас вниз, губить — те же самые действия.
So, where’s karma located? Guru Mahārāj would say, “In the mind.”
Так где же находится карма? Гуру Махарадж говорил: «В уме».
That’s the seat of karmic activity. It’s not the action so much.
Вот место кармической деятельности. Это не само действие как таковое.
That’s why in law when they have a …
Вот почему в суде, когда разбирают...
especially in the case of murder, they will talk about intent.
особенно в случае убийства будут рассматривать намерение.
So, they have to establish criminal intent,
Суду необходимо установить мотив преступления.
that there’s no doubt that someone was murdered; they were killed.
Конечно, факт убийства, преступления налицо, но…
But they say that to determine guilt and subsequent punishment,
скажут так: «Чтобы определить вину и меру последующего наказания,
we need to interrogate the person, find out what were they thinking,
нужно допросить обвиняемого, разобраться в его намерениях —
why did this happen, what’s the cause behind it all.
понять, почему это случилось, что его вынудило к этому.
And when that’s determined, motive, intent, then you can establish innocence or guilt.
И когда мотив, намерение определены, тогда можно утверждать, виновен он или нет».
So, karma is actually like that. It’s not as much the movement,
В вопросах кармы то же самое. Не столько важно само действие,
but the motive for the movement.
как мотив этого действия.